This Christmas, Santa's got a brand new bag.
Jackie Brown is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Quentin Tarantino.
Jackie Brown is a flight attendant who gets caught in the middle of
smuggling cash into the country for her gunrunner boss.
When the cops try to use Jackie to get to her boss, she hatches a plan — with
help from a bail bondsman — to keep the money for herself.
Jackie Brown, played by Pam Grier.
Ordell Robbie, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Louis Gara, played by Robert De Niro.
Melanie Ralston, played by Bridget Fonda.
Ray Nicolette, played by Michael Keaton.
Max Cherry, played by Robert Forster.
Jackie Brown is a 1997 American crime film written and directed by Quentin
Tarantino, based on the 1992 novel Rum Punch by Elmore Leonard.
It stars Pam Grier, Samuel L.
Jackson, Robert Forster, Bridget Fonda, Michael Keaton and Robert De Niro.
In the film, Jackie Brown (Grier), a flight attendant, becomes embroiled in a
battle to smuggle money between the United States and Mexico.
Jackie Brown pays homage to 1970s blaxploitation films, particularly
Coffy and Foxy Brown, both of which also starred Grier.
It is the only feature-length film directed by
Tarantino that was based on another work.
Jackie Brown was released in the United States on
December 25, 1997, by Miramax Films.
It received positive reviews and grossed $74.7
million worldwide on a $12 million budget.
It was both Grier and Forster's first lead role in a major film for many years, and earned a nomination for the Academy
Award for Best Supporting Actor for Forster, and Golden Globe Award nominations for Jackson and Grier.
The film explores themes of airport, based on novel or
book, police, arms deal, stewardess.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.